Hey, you guys ever wonder
why they call it "Thanksgiving"?
너희들 추수감사절이
왜 추수감사절인 줄 아냐?
Okay. Hey, Monica, you're doing
Thanksgiving next week, right?
좋아
모니카, 추수감사절은
네가 준비할 거지?
캐롤이 벤 데리고
플로리다 부모님 댁에 간대
Because Carol's taking Ben
to her parents' place in Florida.
Okay, okay.
I'll make Thanksgiving dinner.
그래, 알았어
추수감사절 만찬은 내게 맡겨
You don't have to beg.
애걸할 필요는 없어
애걸 안 했어
한 번 물어봤잖아
I didn't beg.
I just asked once.
애걸하면 안 돼?
You could beg, you know.
Monica said
I could make dessert this year.
모니카가 올해 디저트는
내가 만들랬어
- 네가 요리를 한다고?
- 그럼, 왜 못해?
-You're gonna cook something?
-Hey, I cook.
껌을 권하는 건 요리가 아냐
Offering people gum is not cooking.
Are you sure Monica said
you could cook this year?
모니카가 요리를 시켰다고?
그런 얘긴 2년 만에 처음이지?
I remember her saying in two years.
You said in two years, right?
그래, 내가 약속했어
No, I promised her.
Are you sure you want to start out with
something as big as Thanksgiving dinner?
근데 추수감사절 저녁은
너한테 좀 벅차지 않을까?
I mean, maybe you wanna try
a little Thanksgiving breakfast?
약소하게 추수감사절 아침이나
추수감사절 간식은 어때?
Maybe a Thanksgiving snack?
Come on, you guys,
I can do this.
사람 무시하지 마
그 피넛버터쿠키 생각 안 나?
Remember, I made those
peanut butter cookies.
걱정도 팔자다, 요리야 쉽지
조리법만 따라하면 되잖아
What are you guys so worried about?
Cooking is easy.
You just follow the recipe.
If it says, "boil two cups of salt,"
you just boil two cups of salt.
소금 두 컵 넣어라?
소금 두 컵 넣지 뭐
The One Where Ross Got High
Okay, great. Bye.
네, 좋아요
끊을게요
추수감사절에 누가 오게?
Guess who's coming
to Thanksgiving dinner?
시드니 포이티에?
Sidney Poitier?
레이첼이 그립다
I miss Rachel.
My parents.
우리 엄마아빠야
Great, they haven't seen the place
since I moved in.
잘됐네, 내가 이 집에
들어오곤 처음이잖아
If you could not mention that
we live together, that'd be great.
우리 함께 산다는 얘기
안 해줬으면 고맙겠어
4시쯤에 먹자
I was thinking we'd eat around 4.
왜 그 얘길 하면 안 되지?
Why can't I tell them
we live together?
우리 사귀는 거 모르셔
주방에서 먹을까?
They don't know we're dating.
Should we eat in the kitchen?
Why haven't you told them?
왜 말씀 안 드렸어?
말씀드리려고 했어, 진짜로
Well, I was going to. I really was.
But then somewhere,
just out of nowhere, I didn't.
근데 어쩌다 보니
말씀을 못 드렸네
왜 얘기를 안 했어
싫어하실까봐?
Why not? Wouldn't they be happy?
저녁은 주방에서 4시야
그때 보자고
So, dinner in the kitchen around 4.
I'll see you then.
- 왜 싫어하시는데?
- 그러니까...
Why wouldn't they be happy?
Well, because...
일단은...
mainly...
자길 싫어하셔
they don't like you.
- 미안해
- 뭐? 어째서?
-I'm sorry.
-What? Why? Why?
자기가 너무 잘난 척하거나
늘 빈정거린다거나
Maybe because you used to be aloof...
or that you're sarcastic
or that you joke around...
농담만 한다거나
or that you throw your clothes
on the couch.
소파 위에 옷을 던지는
버릇 때문이겠지
부모님이 아니라 자기가
날 싫어하는 이유 아냐?
Is this why they don't like me
or you don't like me?
어떻게 생각하시든
얘기를 했어야 되는데
I know I should have told them.
I shouldn't care what they think.
I'm sorry.
미안해
It'll be okay because when
they come over, I will be charming.
괜찮아, 두 분 오시면
내가 잘 모실 거야
날 맘에 들어하시면
그때 얘기하자고
I will make them love me,
then we'll tell them.
그게 잘될까?
Will that work?
나도 꽤 매력적이라고
자기도 넘어왔잖아
I can be pretty charming, babe.
I won you over, didn't l?
엄마아빠가 그렇게까지
취하진 않을 걸?
I don't think you'll ever get
my parents that drunk.
마침 잘됐다, 로스
Hey. Oh, good, Ross.
Your parents like me, right?
너희 부모님 나 좋아하시냐?
Yes, of course they like you.
물론 좋아하시지
모니카 말로는 아니던데?
Monica told me they don't.
Yeah, they don't like you.
맞아, 너 싫어하셔
Do you know why?
혹시 이유를 알아?
Maybe it's because you're sarcastic
or maybe it's because you..
빈정대는 버릇 때문이거나
그것도 아니면...
그 놈의 추측 좀 집어치워
If people don't know,
they shouldn't just guess!
감사할 게 하나도 없는
추수감사절이 또 왔군
Another Thanksgiving
with nothing to give thanks for.
Maybe I give thanks
for you shutting up, huh?
입 다물면 내가 감사할 걸?
Maybe I give thanks by taking
my PlayStation to my place.
플레이스테이션 돌려주면
내가 너한테 감사할 걸?
Maybe I love you.
난 너 좋아할 걸?
- 안녕
- 네
Hey, guys.
뭐해요?
No, I don't want
to play video games, Joey!
난 비디오게임하기 싫다니까
챈들러 집에서
추수감사절 쉴 거예요?
Are you guys going
to Chandler's for Thanksgiving?
네, 왜 그러는데요?
Yeah, why?
댄스하는 친구들이랑 파티를
준비했는데 혹시 맘 있어요?
Me and my friends are
doing Thanksgiving uptown.
I thought you might like to come.
For real?
진짜로?
You should go to Chandler's.
None of us can cook.
그냥 챈들러 집으로 가요
우린 요리를 할 줄 몰라서
종일 술만 마실 거예요
We'll just drink all day.
We go to yours!
물론 그쪽으로 가야죠
We have to stop across the hall
because it's my sister.
여동생 집이라고 매번
저쪽으로 가는 건 안 좋죠
But, you know, actually,
growing up with a sister was nice...
그래도 여동생이랑 자라서
여자를 잘 이해하게 됐답니다
because it helped me
understand women.
Yeah, you should tell
your friends that.
친구들한테 꼭 전해줘요
Okay.
알았어요
How you got three women to marry you,
I'll never know.
어떻게 세 번씩이나
결혼했는지 불가사의다
Hey, Mon, look.
I'm melting butter.
모니카, 나 봐라
나 버터 녹인다
That's great, Rach. You now have
the cooking skills of a hot day.
잘됐다, 삼복더위의
요리법을 익혔구나
- 얘들아
- 어서 와
피비, 이거 봐라
Phoebe, check it out!
For my dessert...
디저트로 정통 영국식
트라이플을 만들기로 했어
I'm making a traditional
English trifle.
Wow. That sounds great!
And what are you making, Monica?
와, 그거 멋지다
모니카, 넌 뭐 만들 건데?
레이첼의 디저트가 너무...
In case Rachel's dessert is
so good that I eat all of it...
맛있어서 내가
다 먹어버리면...
and there's none left
for anybody else!
다른 사람은 못 먹잖아
Nothing.
- 안 만들어
- 안 만들어?
Nothing?
No, sweetie. I trust you.
그래, 널 믿으니까
If I mess this up,
there's nothing else for dessert?
내가 이걸 망치면
디저트는 없는 거야?
You won't mess it up.
망치긴 왜 망쳐
I love that. You really
have faith in me. Thank you.
모니카, 그래도 넌 날
믿어주는구나, 고마워
Question: How do you know
when the butter is done?
질문 하나 할게
다 됐는지는 어떻게 알아?
It's done about two minutes
before it looks like that.
상태를 보아하니
2분전에 다 됐다
- 얘들아
- 우리 왔다
냄새 아주 기가 막히다
-The food smells great, Mon.
-And the place looks so nice.
게다가 분위기도 와따네
얘들아
-Hey, happy Thanksgiving, everybody!
-Happy Thanksgiving!
행복한 추수감사절 맞아라
-Well, this has been great.
-See you.
- 정말 수고 많았다
- 또 보자
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
어딜 가려고?
Where you going?
조이 룸메이트가 뭘 하는데
거기 좀 들렀다 올까 하고
We did say we'd stop by this little
thing Joey's roommate is having.
그 끝내주는 댄서 재닌?
Oh, Janine,
the really hot dancer girl?
Some would say she's attractive, yes.
매력적이라고 할 수도 있지
Who else is going to be there?
거기 또 누가 오는데?
재닌 친구들 몇 명
Her friends.
댄서 친구들?
Her dancer friends?
Yes! All right?
그래, 좀 가면 안 되냐?
끝내주는 댄서들이 몰려와
All of her hot dancer friends
are gonna be there...
and they'll be drinking and dancing
and we really want to go!
술 마시고 춤추고
진짜 가고 싶단 말이야
Dude, we were good.
야, 잘 나가다 왜 이래
You're not going. You said
you'd eat here and you'll eat here.
두 사람 아무 데도 못 가
약속했으니까 여기서 먹어
Yeah, and leaving us
to go see hot dancer girls...
우릴 두고 딴 데서 재미 보는 건
전혀 '추수감사절'스럽지 않아
is not very Thanksgiving-y.
최초의 추수감사절이랑
비슷한 거야
Oh, but it is.
It's like the first Thanksgiving when
the Indians and Pilgrims sat down.
인디언과 청교도들이
식탁에 함께 앉았듯이
Then the Indians taught
the Pilgrims...
그래
인디언이 청교도에게 신세계의
재미가 뭔지 가르쳐주는 거지
...what it meant to be hot
in the New World!
너희들 여기 있는 게 좋겠다
Fellas, I really think
you should stay here.
You're just jealous
because you can't go.
넌 못 간다고 재 뿌리냐?
That is so not true.
말도 안 되는 소리 말고
- 안녕, 얘들아
- 우리 왔다
-Hello, everybody!
-Hi!
아빠
Hi, Dad. Mom.
엄마
보세요, 챈들러가 왔어요
Look! Look who it is!
It's Chandler!
그렇구나, 잘 지냈니?
Oh, yes, of course.
Hello, Chandler.
두 분 너무 좋아 보이네요
와주셔서 감사합니다
Mr. and Mrs. Geller,
you look wonderful.
It is great to have you here.
Let us take your coats.
코트 벗으시죠
Whoa, it snowing out there?
밖에 눈 오나요?
아니네
No.
모니카, 정말 먹음직스럽구나
이쪽으로 일자리를 찾아봐라
Monica, all this food looks wonderful.
You should do this for a living.
Okay, I have dandruff.
There's no need to laugh and point.
그래, 나 비듬 좀 있는데
손가락질하며
비웃을 건 없잖나
아빠가 한 농담이
재미있다는 거예요
Chandler was laughing at your joke.
그 농담 하나도 안 웃겼어
My joke wasn't funny.
Chandler laughs at everything.
챈들러는 잘 웃어요
좋은 점 중의 하나죠
That's one of the great things about him.
레이첼
Rach, I just remembered.
왜?
방금 생각났는데
나 간밤에 겔러 씨 꿈꿨어
I had a dream
about Mr. Geller last night.
- 정말?
- 그래
Really?
I dreamt that he saved me
from a burning building...
불타는 건물에서 날 구했는데
정말 용감하고 힘도 세더라
and he was so brave and so strong.
오늘 보니까 느낌이 확 다르다
And it's making me look at him
totally differently.
He used to be just
"Jack Geller, Monica and Ross' dad."
전엔 그냥 친구 아빠
잭 겔러로 보였는데
Now he's "Jack Geller, dream hunk."
이젠 꿈속의 사나이 잭 겔러야
I don't know. To me,
he'll always be "Jack Geller...
글쎄
내겐 항상 옷 갈아입는데
쳐들어오는 잭 겔러거든
walks in while you're changing."
You know, Dad, Chandler is one
of Ross' very best friends.
아빠, 챈들러는 오빠랑
제일 친한 친구예요
그래, 안다
Yes, I know.
로스는 정말 멋진 녀석이죠
Ross sure is a great guy.
I've always felt that
how a man turns out...
옛말에도 있지만 아들은
아버지를 닮는다잖아요
is a reflection on his father.
나도 그렇게 생각한다네
자네 부친은 뭘 하시나?
I always thought that too.
Tell me, what does your father do?
He's a headliner of a...
간판급 스타시죠...
gay burlesque show.
게이 스트립쇼의
You're killing us.
Will you serve the dessert already?
레이첼, 정말 미치겠다
아직 디저트 덜 됐냐?
There's drunken dancers a-waiting!
술 취한 댄서들이 대기 중이야
이것 봐, 멋있지?
Look at it. Isn't it beautiful?
Yeah. What is it?
그래, 그게 뭔데?
It's a trifle.
It's got all these layers.
트라이플인데
층이 여러 개야
먼저 카스텔라를 깔고
다음은 잼과 커스터드
First there's a layer
of ladyfingers, then jam...
then custard,
which I made from scratch...
이건 처음부터 내 작품이지
그리고 라즈베리
카스텔라 좀 더
then raspberries,
more ladyfingers...
then beef sauteed
with peas and onions...
완두콩과 양파를 넣고
살짝 튀긴 쇠고기
then a little bit more custard...
커스터드 더 깔고
then bananas and then
I put whipped cream on top.
바나나 올린 다음
휩 크림으로 마무리
바나나 바로 전에 뭐라고?
What was the one right before bananas?
The beef.
Yeah, that was weird to me too.
쇠고기
그건 나도 좀 이상한데
But then I thought,
"Well, there's minced-meat pie."
영국 디저트 중엔
다진 쇠고기 파이도 있어
That's an English dessert.
그쪽 사람들 이상한 거
많이 넣어 먹잖아
These people just put
strange things in their food.
Can I borrow rum from your place?
그건 그렇고 너희
럼주 좀 써도 되니?
- 물론이지
- 그래
Yeah, sure.
나 없다고 몰래 맛보지 마
While I'm gone,
don't you sneak a taste.
알았어
Beef in a dessert?
디저트에 쇠고기?
No, no, no. There is no way.
그럴 리가 없어
I know. And only one layer of jam?
그러게, 게다가 잼이
한 층밖에 안 들어가?
What is up with that?
그게 사람이 먹는 거냐?
이런!
Oh, my God.
The pages are stuck together.
페이지가 붙어있어
챈들러!
Chandler!
Oh, my God. She made
half an English trifle and...
맙소사, 절반은
영국식 트라이플이고...
half a shepherd's pie!
나머지 반은 셰퍼드 파이야
돌겠다, 그럼 다시
만들겠다고 덤빌 텐데
Man, now she's gonna start all over.
신세계의 뜨거운 여자들
물 건너가는 거 아냐?
We're never gonna get to introduce
the hot girls to the New World.
아냐, 망쳤다는 얘기만
안 하면 갈 수 있어
No, no, we will.
We just won't tell her she messed up.
쇠고기 커스터드를 먹으라고?
Just let her serve
the beef-custard thing?
Yeah. It'll be like
a funny Thanksgiving story.
그래, 이것도 즐거운
추억이 될 거야
Vomiting stories are funny, I guess.
토하는 추억 즐겁기도 하겠다
Joey. God, your
apartment is, like, 100 degrees.
조이, 너희 아파트 너무 덥다
속옷만 입고 돌아다니고 싶지?
Did it make you want
to walk around in your underwear?
No.
아니
Still not hot enough!
더 올려야겠네
- 레이첼
- 그래
Rachel. Okay, look at him.
겔러 씨를 봐
차돌처럼 단단한 손
Look at those strong hands.
될 수만 있다면 나도 저...
연유 깡통이 되고 싶다
Oh, what I wouldn't give
to be that can of condensed milk.
Chandler was just saying
how beautiful your sweater is.
엄마, 챈들러가 엄마 스웨터
너무 예쁘대요
고맙다, 챈들러
최근에 샀단다
Thank you. I just bought it.
정말 예쁘네요
크림색에 쫙 달라붙는 게...
Yes, well, it's very beautiful and
it's cream-colored and tight and...
I don't mean tight. It's not tight.
Not that I was looking at...
그 정도 달라붙어선
잘 보이지도 않고...
What's the matter with him?
이 친구 왜 이러나?
I think he's stoned again.
또 약 먹었나봐요
What?
- 네?
- 뭐라고요?
잠깐 나 좀 보자
I need to talk to you.
두 분이 왜 널
싫어하는지 알 거 같다
I think I might know why
my parents don't like you.
그래? 왜지?
Why?
- 이건 오래 전 얘긴데...
- 그래
Okay, remember we were young.
2학년 봄방학 때 내가
침실에서 대마초를 피우는데
Spring break, sophomore year,
I got high in my bedroom...
두 분이 들어오셔서
냄새를 맡은 거야
and my parents walked in
and smelled it...
그래서 난 네가 피우다가
창 밖으로 달아났다고 했어
so I told them that you had gotten
stoned and jumped out the window.
- 뭐? 왜 그랬어?
- 몰라
Why did you do that?
I don't know. Yours was the first
name that popped into my head.
그냥 네 이름이 생각나더라
미안하다, 문제가 되리라고는
생각 못했어
I didn't think it'd matter.
지금 문제가 되잖아
How could it not matter?
네가 지금까지 친구로 남아서
내 여동생과 살게 될 줄 알았나?
How was I to know
we'd be friends after college...
and you'd be living with my sister?
영원한 친구 운운했던 건 뭐야
What about the
"friends forever" stuff?
I don't know. I was all high.
글쎄, 약에 취했었나봐
자기가 오빠까지 꼬드겨
대마초 피운다고 가보래
Mom and Dad sent me to find out
if you were trying to get Ross stoned.
Your parents caught Ross smoking pot
in college, and he blamed it on me!
얘가 대마초 피우다 걸린 걸
나한테 다 뒤집어씌웠대
I can't believe you!
어떻게 그럴 수가 있어?
We haven't told them we're together
because they hate me, so fix this.
두 분이 날 싫어하셔서
같이 산다는 말도 못해
사실대로 말할래?
알았어, 대마초 피운 건
네가 아니었다고 할게
Okay, okay, I'll tell them
it wasn't Chandler who got high.
- 좋아
- 그럼 누구라고 하지?
Now, who should I say it was?
You! It's not like it's a big deal.
You don't still do it or anything.
오빠잖아
지금 하는 것도 아닌데
무슨 걱정이야?
알았어, 그럼 누구 꼬임에
넘어갔다고 할까?
All right. Now, who should I say
tricked me into doing it?
Nobody. You're gonna go out there
and tell them exactly what happened.
그런 사람 없어
당장 나가서 사실대로 말해
- 그래야 돼?
- 그럼!
-Really?
-Yes!
알았어
Okay.
Wait, is there anything else
I should know?
- 잠깐, 다른 건 없겠지?
- 그럼, 오...
No.. Oh, yeah....
아니다
아버지 레코드를 전자레인지로
태워먹은 것도 너야
You microwaved a bunch
of my dad's records.
Why?
왜?
Evidently, you weren't very good
at handling your high.
넌 대마초 피우고 나면
앞뒤 분간을 못하거든
Dad, please don't pick
your teeth out here.
아빠
여기서 이 쑤시지 마세요
- 발 올려놓으실 거면...
- 모니카, 이 분 건드리지 마!
And if you're gonna put your feet up..
Leave him alone!
Will you hurry up?
빨리 좀 해라
재닌 친구들은
다 댄서란 말 못 들었어?
Did you not hear me when I told you
that Janine's friends are dancers?
술도 엄청 마실 거야
And that they're gonna
be drinking a lot?
No, I did. But tell me again
because it's so romantic.
다시 한 번 얘기해 줘
너무 로맨틱하다 얘
너무 느리잖아
빨리 좀 저어
You're whipping so slow.
Do it faster!
조이, 실수하고 싶지 않아
I don't want to make any mistakes!
하나뿐인 디저트를 망치면
나중에 다들 이럴 걸?
If I screw it up,
everybody's gonna be like:
'레이첼이 트라이플 망쳤던
추수감사절 생각나니?'
"Oh, remember that Thanksgiving
when Rachel screwed up the trifle?"
만드는 건 내 책임이니까
넌 먹을 걱정이나 해
Just let me worry about making it,
and you just worry about eating it.
걱정하고 있어
Oh, I am.
오빠가 싫다면 내가 할 거야
-If you don't tell them, then I will.
-Okay. Fine.
알았어, 할게
Ross, can I talk to you for a second?
로스, 얘기 좀 할까?
잠깐만 기다려줄래?
부모님께 드릴 말씀이 있어
Can it wait? I have
to tell my parents something.
못 기다려? 별수 없지
No, it can't? Okay.
아무래도 레이첼한테
디저트 망쳤단 얘길 해야겠어
We have to tell Rachel
she messed up her dessert.
뭐? 다들 왜 이래
What? What is with everybody?
오늘은 추수감사절이지
진실의 날이 아냐
It's Thanksgiving, not...
Truth Day!
저 바나나 고기범벅이 올라오면
Look, when everyone eats
that banana-meat thing...
레이첼은 웃음거리가 돼
그럼 좋겠어?
they'll all make fun of her.
Do you want that?
좋아, 다른 사람들한테
맛있게 먹어달라고 하자
We'll just get everyone
to act like they like it.
그럼 레이첼도 괜찮고 우린
고구마파이 먹을 수 있잖아
That way, no one makes fun of her...
and we still get to go
to sweet-potato pie.
야, 걔들은 먹이가 아냐
Dude, they're not objects.
농담이야, 내가 얘기할게
넌 레이첼을 맡아
Just kidding. I'll talk to them.
You distract her.
레이첼, 밖에서
잠깐 얘기 좀 하자
Hey, Rach, can I talk to you
outside for a sec?
Okay.
알았어
뭔데 그래?
What's up, Ross?
So....
그러니까...
Thanksgiving.
추수감사절이네
The holiday season is upon us.
바야흐로 명절 시즌이야, 음?
그래
그리고...
And...
you look nice today.
너 오늘 정말 예쁘다
안 돼, 로스
이러지 마
-Oh, no. No, Ross, don't do this.
-What?
뭘?
우리가 다시 사귀는 건
좋은 생각이 아냐
I don't think us getting back
together is a good idea.
엥?
I thought this might happen today.
오늘쯤 이럴 줄 알았어, 로스
물론 명절이라 힘들겠지
I know the holidays can be rough...
이럴 때 혼자라는 게
고통스러울 거야
and it's probably hard
for you to be alone right now.
너도 혼자야
You're alone.
아냐, 난 피비랑 살잖아
No, I live with Phoebe.
넌 아무도 없는 혼자야
안 그래?
I mean, you're alone-alone.
And it's just not the time
for us. I'm sorry.
지금 이래선 안 될 거 같아
미안해
Oh, well.
Can't blame a guy for trying.
좋아, 한 번 그래본 거야
맛있게 먹어주는 게 힘들다면
연기학교에서 배운 게 있어요
And if anyone needs help
pretending to like it...
I learned some things in acting
class. Try rubbing your stomach.
배를 문지르는 거죠
아니면 이렇게, 음...
Or saying, "Mmm."
참, 미소도 좋아요
Smiling.
알았죠?
I'm not gonna pay
for those acting classes anymore.
그 연기학교에는
돈 내기 싫어진다
Rachel, there you are.
Let's serve that dessert already!
레이첼, 어디 갔었어?
빨리 디저트 줘야지
Joey, you have to stop rushing me.
You don't get any dessert.
조이, 그렇게 자꾸 보채면
디저트 못 먹을 줄 알아
Really?
진짜?
No, just kidding.
I would never do that to you.
아니, 농담이야
너한테 그럴 수 있나
Okay, everybody, it's trifle time.
자, 여러분
트라이플 나갑니다
So, Rach, this is a traditional
English trifle, isn't it?
그런데 레이첼
이게 정통 영국식
트라이플이라고?
그럼
-It sure is.
-Wow.
쇠고기를 넣었니
가지를 넣었니?
So did you make it
with beef or eggplant?
쇠고기
-Beef.
-I can't have any. I don't eat meat.
그럼 곤란하지
난 고기 안 먹잖아
모니카, 너한테
첫 시식의 영광을 줄게
Monica, I want you
to have the first taste.
Really?
정말?
Wait, you only got whipped cream.
잠깐, 크림만 뜨지 말고
밑에까지 푹 퍼야지
You gotta take a bite
with all the layers.
알았어
You dropped a pea.
콩 떨어졌다
Well?
어때?
It's good.
맛있다 얘
진짜? 얼마나 맛있어?
Really? How good?
너무 맛있어서
나 혼자만 먹기 아까운 걸?
It's so good that I feel selfish...
about being the only one
who's eating it.
다들 얼마나 맛있는지
먹어봤음 좋겠어
I think we should have everyone
taste how good it is.
특히 오빠가
Especially Ross.
This is so good that I'm gonna
go enjoy it on the balcony.
너무 맛있으니까
발코니에 가서 먹을래
디저트를 음미하면서
풍경을 감상하고 싶어
So that I can enjoy the view
whilst I enjoy my dessert.
내 친구 매리한테 전화해서
너무 맛있다고 자랑해야겠다
I've gotta call my friend...
and tell her how good
this is from Monica's room.
I'll help dial.
내가 걸어줄게
I'm gonna go into the bathroom...
난 화장실에서 먹는 모습을
거울로 지켜보면서 먹을래
so I can look at it
in the mirror as I eat it.
What was that all about?
Does it not taste good?
다들 왜 이러는 거야
맛이 없어? 어디 봐
-Let me try it.
-No, no!
뭐야, 안 돼!
All gone!
식사 끝
So good.
황홀하다
Maybe Chandler has some left.
챈들러 게 좀 남았을 거야
It tastes like feet.
꼭 발을 씹는 기분이다
I like it!
난 맛있어
Are you kidding?
장난하냐?
재료는 훌륭하잖아
커스터드 맛있지
What's not to like? Custard, good.
Jam, good. Meat, good.
잼도 맛있지
고기도 맛있지
새가 달려들어 채갔다고?
So a bird just grabbed it...
and then tried
to fly away with it...
그걸 들고 날아가려다...
and then just dropped it
on the street?
길에 떨어뜨렸어?
If it's any consolation,
before the bird dropped it...
그래, 어쨌든 떨어뜨리기 전에
아주 맛있게 먹는 것 같더라
he seemed to enjoy it.
Rachel, come here.
레이첼, 잠깐만
들어봐
잠깐 눈을 붙였는데
또 겔러 씨 꿈을 꿨어
I was taking my Thanksgiving nap
and I had another dream.
꼭 들어야 해?
-Do I want to hear this?
-I don't know, let's see.
그러니까 들어봐
꿈에서 우리가 결혼하려는데
또 불을 끄러 사라져 버린 거야
I dreamt we were getting married...
and he left because
he had to go fight a fire.
난 어떤 나이트클럽에 갔는데
다른 여자랑 거기 있더라니까
So I went to a nightclub
and I saw him making out with a girl.
Oh, my God, he dream-cheated on you!
세상에, 꿈에서 당했구나
But then Jacques Cousteau came...
때마침 나타난 자크 쿠스토가
날 대신해서 한방 먹여줬어
and he kicked his ass
for betraying me.
정말 근사하더라
So cool!
Then he took me diving
and introduced me to his sea horse...
그리곤 바다에 들어가서
해마를 소개시켜줬는데
그 해마 녀석이 내가 좋다고
달려드는데 사람 미치겠더라
who was coming on to me.
Please, that is not gonna happen.
오늘 긴 벨트를
차고 오길 잘했구나
Boy, I'm glad I wore
the big belt today.
Five minutes ago, a line like that
would have floored me.
5분전에 저런 대사를
들었으면 쓰러졌겠지만
But now, nothing. Well, not nothing.
I am still a woman.
지금은 별거 아냐
아니긴 뭐가 아냐
나도 여잔데
Ross? Let's go.
오빠, 말해야지
아무래도 이런 사안은 말보다
편지를 쓰는 게 좋지 않을까?
Oh, yeah.
About telling Mom and Dad...
I was thinking about
maybe writing a letter.
그래, 이제 됐어
오빤 기회를 놓쳤어
That's it. You've had your chance.
뭐야?
엄마, 아빠
Mom, Dad. Ross smoked pot in college.
오빠가 대학 때
대마초를 피웠대요
뭐?
이런 고자질쟁이!
You are such a tattletale!
엄마, 아빠
Mom, Dad...
you remember that time
you walked in my room...
제 방에서 마리화나 냄새가
났던 때 기억하시죠?
and smelled marijuana?
Yes.
그래
전 그때 대마초를 피운 게
챈들러였다고 말씀드렸지만...
I told you it was Chandler...
who was smoking the pot but...
it was me. I'm sorry.
실은 저였어요, 죄송해요
It was you?
너였어?
And Dad,
Chandler didn't melt your records.
그리고 아빠
레코드 태워먹은 것도
챈들러가 아니라
Ross did.
오빠예요
- 이게 사실이냐?
- 또 있어요
-Is that true?
-And Dad...
you know that mailman
that you got fired?
플레이보이를 훔친 사람도
그 해고된 집배원이 아니라
He didn't steal your Playboys.
Ross did.
오빠라고요
현관 그네의자 해먹은 건
허리케인이 아니라 모니카래요
Well, Hurricane Gloria didn't break
the porch swing. Monica did!
오빠는 1년 전에
박물관 관뒀대요
Ross hasn't worked
at the museum for a year!
모니카랑 챈들러는
동거한대요!
Monica and Chandler
are living together!
오빤 레이첼이랑 결혼하고
금방 이혼했대요, 또!
Ross married Rachel in Vegas!
And got divorced! Again!
난 자크 쿠스토를 사랑해요!
I love Jacques Cousteau!
트라이플에 쇠고기를
넣으면 안 되는 거였어
I wasn't supposed
to put beef in the trifle!
난 나가고 싶어요!
I want to go!
30초 동안 너무 많은
정보를 얻었구나
That's a lot of information
to get in 30 seconds.
좋아
All right. Joey, if you want
to leave, just leave.
조이, 가고 싶으면 가거라
레이첼, 트라이플에는
쇠고기를 넣으면 안 된다
Rachel, no, you weren't supposed
to put beef in the trifle.
맛이 영 별로였어
It did not taste good.
피비
Phoebe, I'm sorry...
미안하지만 자크 쿠스토는
이미 세상을 떠난 것 같다
but I think
Jacques Cousteau is dead.
Monica, why you felt
you had to hide the fact...
모니카
왜 그런 중요한 사실을
숨기려고 했는지 모르겠구나
that you're in an important
relationship is beyond me.
그네의자 사건은
대충 짐작했었다
And we kind of figured
about the porch swing.
Ross.
로스
대마초?
이혼? 또?
Drugs?
Divorced again?
왜 그랬니, 아들아
What happened, son?
다 꼬임에 빠져서 그런 거예요
I got tricked into all those things.
챈들러
Chandler, you've been
Ross' best friend all these years...
얘가 마약에 중독됐는데도
끝까지 친구로 남아줬구나
stuck by him
during the drug problems...
이제 모니카까지 떠맡고
and now you've taken on
Monica as well.
Well, I don't know what to say.
글쎄, 무슨 말을 더 하겠니
넌 참 인간이 됐다
You're a wonderful human being.
- 감사합니다
- 아냐
-Thank you!
-No.
우리가 고맙지
Thank you!
그리고 너희 두 녀석은
어떡해야 내 직성이 풀릴까
Monica and Ross, I don't know what
I'm gonna do about the two of you.
I'll talk to them.
제가 잘 얘기하죠
얘들아, 바나나에
크림에 쇠고기였는데
You guys, it was bananas...
cream and beef!
내 기분을 생각해서 그걸
먹어주다니 믿을 수가 없어
I just cannot believe that you ate
that so that I wouldn't feel bad.
사실 난 안 먹었어
아직 화장실에 있을 거야
Well, actually, I didn't eat mine.
It's still in the bathroom.
그거 내가 먹었는데
No, I ate that.
우리 건 모니카 방에 뒀단다
And we left ours in Monica's bedroom.
아뇨, 것도 제가 다 먹었어요
Nope, got it and got yours too.
Chandler, are you gonna stick
with that bird story?
챈들러, 넌 아직도
새라고 우길래?
엄청 큰 새가 덮쳤다니깐
It was a big bird.
Swooped right in there.
-Hi.
-Oh, Janine.
나 왔어요
재닌, 벌써 끝난 거예요?
-It's not over, is it?
-Yeah.
네, 명절에 그러고 있자니
외롭고 처량한 기분이 들어서
We all got depressed.
The holidays and everything, we're alone.
Yeah, well, at least you have Joey.
그쪽은 조이가 있잖아요
로스는 진짜 혼자예요
But Ross is really alone.
Well, you're always welcome here.
언제든 환영해요
This is my mom and my dad.
우리 엄마아빠예요
이쪽은 재닌
-This is Janine.
-Nice to meet you.
반갑습니다
-I think we've already met.
-Really?
벌써 한 번 봤죠?
그래요?
전 건너편에 살아요
I live across the hall.
You walked in on me when I was changing.
옷 갈아입을 때
들어오셨잖아요